shoemetro.com 2017-11-02

# Security Policy

As ShoeMetro’s (“ShoeMetro”, “us”, “our” or “we”) valued customer, we respect you and your privacy and have taken steps to protect your personal information.

This Privacy Policy explains what information we gather about you when you visit this Web site at ShoeMetro.com (“Website”), how we use that information, and the safeguards we have in place for this information. By visiting this Website, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy only applies to information we collect online at ShoeMetro.com, but does not cover information collected, if any, in the B2B portions of this website.

**INFORMATION COLLECTION**

Our goal in collecting information from you is to provide an efficient, meaningful and customized experience.

**1\. General Browsing Information**

When you visit this Website, we may automatically collect information gathered from your computer. We collect navigational information about where you go on our Website, how many visits you make to the site, when the site is visited, and other non-personally identifiable information (for example, this can include domain type, browser version, service provider, IP address). The navigational information helps us better understand a visitor’s experience at ShoeMetro.com and improve upon that experience by recognizing and delivering more of the features, services and products our visitors prefer.

**2\. Personal Information**

In addition, you may voluntarily provide information online at ShoeMetro.com if you elect to complete an online registration form; register for a free shoe giveaway; request us to notify you when we receive a new brand, new product style, or product size; sign up for our email newsletter and special offers; or sign up for the ShoeMetro.com Shoe Digest. Categories of information collected include name, address, email address, recipient’s name and email address, order information, telephone number, credit card/debit card information, birth month and day, your review of our products, saved searches, preferred brands or messages.

**OUR USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

ShoeMetro uses the personal information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * to deliver products that you have ordered, fulfill requests that you have created and process your return or exchange; 
  * to understand your needs and preferences, possibly through surveys, product evaluations or cookies;
  * to develop, market and sell products and services to you and to tailor your experience on the ShoeMetro.com website to your interests;
  * to contact you or the product recipient(s) in the event of order or delivery difficulties;
  * to manage and develop ShoeMetro’s business and operations, administer accounts, collect and process payments;
  * to respond to your inquiries;
  * to send you updates about our products, promotions and events; and
  * to deliver information through the various communication channels you have provided to us about our products or website, including adding you to a ShoeMetro email list or to our customer phone and mail marketing list when you register for an account or make a purchase.

If you create or modify your ShoeMetro.com account you may save personal information in that account and we will access this saved information to make your shopping quicker and easier. Any credit card/debit card information will be encrypted by the use of a “token” for security purposes.

If at any time you would like to stop future delivery of promotional email, please follow the removal instructions located at the bottom of each message. Asking us to stop delivery of future promotional email will not prevent you from receiving email communications relating to any online order you place at ShoeMetro.com, requests to participate in surveys about our products other operational email communications or emails forwarded to you by a friend that tell you about our products.

If you submit a product review, rate a product or provide a testimonial statement about your shopping experience with us, your general geographic location may be visible to other users but your email address will be kept private. We are not responsible for any personally identifiable information that you choose to submit as part of your review or testimonial.

To ensure compliance with federal law, ShoeMetro does not knowingly collect or maintain information provided by children under the age of 13.

**DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**

We use third parties to help us provide services to you such as fulfilling orders, processing payments, monitoring online activity at ShoeMetro.com, conducting surveys, maintaining our database, administering emails and administering drawings or contests. Third parties also provide aggregate, comparative information on the performance of our site to us and a select group.

To help you buy products and provide customer service to you, we must provide your credit card number to financial services corporations such as credit card processors and issuers. When we submit your credit card number for authorization, we and related third parties utilize data encryption technologies to protect your information.

If you make a purchase on this Website, or create or modify a ShoeMetro membership account, your name, mailing address, phone number or purchase information may be made available to other companies or co-brand partners who may provide you with information about their products or services or the products and services of their affiliates.

If, after placing an order on this Website, you choose to provide feedback on your experience on a third party’s web site, your feedback is collected by independent sources, is at all times governed by the third party’s privacy policy, and is not governed by this Privacy Policy.

We may be required to disclose specific information about you if necessary to do so by law or based on our good faith belief that it is necessary to enforce or apply our [Terms of Use](https://www.shoemetro.com/t-termsofuse.aspx "Terms of Use"), conform or comply with the law or is necessary to protect ShoeMetro, the users of our website or others.

If we merge with, acquire, or become acquired by another business entity, some or all of the personal information collected about you would be shared with this entity, as well as retained by ShoeMetro.

We may share general, non-personal information (such as the number of daily visitors to a particular web page, or the size of an order placed on a certain date) with third parties such as advertising partners. This information does not directly personally identify you or any user.

**COOKIES AND RELATED TECHNOLOGIES**

We utilize cookies and related technologies to speed your navigation of this Website, recognize you when you visit, grant you access privileges and track your use of this Website.

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored as text files by your Web browser on your computer’s hard drive. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. At your option, you may elect to refuse cookies from web sites or remove cookies from your hard drive. If you do so, you will not be able to access or use portions of this Website as cookies are often required to enable you to select and place products in an online shopping cart and purchase those products. Cookies allow us to keep a record of your browsing activity and purchase(s) so we can make the Website more responsive to your needs. We do not use cookies or spyware to infiltrate your hard drive to gather information.

We may employ third-party advertising companies to help tailor Website content or to serve advertisements on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies to measure advertising effectiveness such as which web pages are visited or what products are purchased and in what amount. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies is not linked to any of the personal information we collect from you.

This Website’s server(s) automatically recognizes the Internet URL from which you access this Website. We may also log your Internet protocol (“IP”) address, Internet service provider, and date/time stamp for system administration, order verification, internal marketing and system troubleshooting purposes, as an IP address may indicate the physical location of your computer on the Internet.

**DATA AND SECURITY**

This Website incorporates physical, electronic and administrative procedures to protect your personal information, including Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) encryption for all ShoeMetro.com financial transactions. We also protect your personal information within our facilities and internally restrict access to your personal information to employees who need access to your personal information to perform a specific job functions. We rely on third party service providers for the physical security of some of our computer hardware, software systems and this Website. While we implement the above security measures on this site, you should be aware that one-hundred percent (100%) security is not always possible.

**OPT OUT AND CORRECTION REQUESTS**

Upon your request, we will take any and all reasonable steps to: (i) correct or update your personal information; (ii) stop sending emails to your email address; and/or (iii) disable your account to prevent any future purchases through that account. You can make these requests in the Customer Service section of this Website, or by telephoning or emailing your request to our Customer Support department. Please take care not to email your credit card number or other sensitive information.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY POLICY  
_NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS - YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS_ **

ShoeMetro collects various types of personal information about you both online (at ShoeMetro.com) and offline during the course of our customer relationship. Under California law, if you are a resident of California, you may make a written request to ShoeMetro to request how we have shared your information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. In response to your written request, ShoeMetro is allowed to provide you with a notice describing the cost-free means to opt-out of our sharing your information with third parties with whom we do not share the same brand name, if the third party will use it for their direct marketing purposes.

ShoeMetro may permit third parties to track the individual visitors to its website and the activities of those visitors on the website over time. Currently, ShoeMetro does not offer the option for its website visitors to make a “Do Not Track” election and does not have the capability to respond to electronic “Do Not Track” signals. ShoeMetro reserves the right to add such capability to its website at any time in the future and will notify website visitors of this change in capability through an update to this Privacy Policy.

ShoeMetro has chosen to provide you with a cost-free means to opt-out of such sharing, which you can accomplish by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) If you would like to instruct us to no longer share your personal information with third parties who will use it for direct marketing purposes, please send an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4033212c25330033282f252d2534322f6e232f2d).

If you have any questions about this opt-out procedure, please write to the email address provided above.

**PRIVACY POLICY UPDATES**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 8, 2017. Please check here periodically for notice of updates to this Privacy Policy.

If you have any concerns about the Terms of Use or Privacy Policy, contact us at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
